Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Hey, heat. Hey, heat.
Heat. Heat. N.
This is
heat.
Heat. Heat. N.
Hey,
hey, hey.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Welcome back Living Mana Church family.
We are so happy that you have continued
to worship with us. Thank you for
finding uh joining I should say the new
link um because we did we this is a new
link that you're on and so we are
thankful that you were able to make your
way here with us for the divine worship
service. You know I have to say that
Sabbath school was really very exciting
to talk about the app. It was amazing to
be able to share with many of you what
the photo theology
um suite is like and how you can learn
and go so much deeper into the Bible.
Our special guest helped with that as
well, sharing their um things that they
loved so much about the app and how it's
helping them to grow um in the Bible and
to go deeper um into the word of God.
And so we are so uh just so thankful for
that. And if you missed it, go back and
rewatch that or watch it for the first
time because it's definitely something
that you're going to want uh to know
more about um and to be able to share
with others um as well. So, please let
us know if you're just joining us uh for
the first time or you were here and you
didn't tell us before where you were
viewing from, please let us know where
you are watching from. Put your name in
the chat as well so we can say your name
because sometimes the handles don't
match the name. I want to welcome you
personally. So, please put where you're
viewing from and if this is your first
time, put a one in the chat. We want to
tell you all about Living Mana Church.
So, again, we're just so thankful that
you are here uh with us today and are
worshiping with us. Want to welcome
Christie from South Carolina. Um it's
such a it's so good to see you here
Christie on the Sabbath to and you're
here with Living Man of Church
worshiping with us. So we know that we
have viewing viewers from all around the
world and we want to hear from everyone
uh who would who is viewing now and we
want to say a special welcome to you.
It's just a blessing to be here with all
of you uh on the Sabbath just to spend
time worshiping God, fellowshipping with
all of you, praying, studying the Bible.
It's a blessing uh just to worship with
you again. Want to say welcome to from
someone in Oklahoma. Good to have you
here at Living Mana Church. I'm so glad
that you are here uh with us today. Uh
we have somebody from New Jersey.
Welcome. Uh we have from Tennessee. Good
to see all of you here. We have um Okay,
we have brother Kashif who was just uh
on with us as a special guest. He is
viewing from the Bronx. Welcome um again
to be here with us at Living Mana
Church. And we have someone from St.
Albins's, New York. It's going up
faster. Sorry I missed your name.
Welcome. Renee from California. Good to
see you here, Renee. Everton from uh
Jamaica. Good to see you. Welcome. And
happy Sabbath to you. We have Diane from
Fort Worth, Texas. Good to have you here
uh with us at Living Mana Church. Such a
blessing to have all of you. Just want
to let you guys know how you can stay
connected to Living Mana Church. Um, the
way that you're going to be able to do
that is you're going to want to sign up
to get text alerts. If you're here in
North America, you will be able to get
text alerts. And there on your screen
tells you how you're able to do that.
You just text LMLC. You dial 855207-4107
and text LMC. And that will
automatically sign you up uh to get text
alerts from Living Manage Church. You're
probably thinking like, why do I want to
do that? Because live when you sign up
to get text alerts, you're able to get
reminders when we're about to go live.
Just like we had to create a new link
today, you would have gotten information
on um your phone to tell you how to do
that so you can continue uh to watch.
And so all of our programming all
throughout the week and um on Sabbath
there is a there is a link that goes out
and it tells you or an announcement that
goes out and it just tells you in 20
minutes we'll be live and uh this is
what is happening. Sometimes there's
other information that we want to share.
It's just a way to stay connected. But
as you know we are an international
church. Everyone is not here in America.
So if you are international you're going
to want to sign up for Mighty Networks.
And I always have to amend that
statement just a little bit. It's not
just for our international viewing
audience or members. The Mighty Networks
is for everyone. As you heard during the
Sabbath school, um if you're wanting to
get more information about the photo
theology suite, there's a whole section
on Mighty Network. So, you can get that
information. Um if you're going to want
to learn about our um our our small
groups, you're going to want that. Those
are on Mighty Network. Our afterglow
after the sermon is over uh is on Mighty
Networks. That is our virtual church
home. So, you're going to want to
download Mighty Networks and that um
link is in the chat. So, you will be
able uh to do that. So, that again is
our virtual church home. You're going to
get to know people there. Our our
leaders for um our small groups, they're
all there. Everything is there. So
whether you are international or if you
are um here in America, it's all right
there. So that is what you're going to
want to do and the link for that is in
the chat. That's how you stay uh
connected.
We want to uh also let you know that we
have programming for kids, LMOC kids,
and that starts on um Saturday morning
at well, Saturday morning here in
America, or I should say in the central
part of America, Central time, 11:30. Um
and so they uh start um on Zoom. And
then um if you want more information
about that, you can text kids to the 855
number to sign your child up um or to a
grandchild, a niece or nephew. Also, if
you're out of the country, please email
LMC kids at living.urch and the
leadership will get back to you so we
can get uh the child that you want to be
a part of lc kids um to be a part of it.
want to remind you guys that we have a
there's hangouts. Hangouts is just what
it sounds like. Um it is all right. I'm
not going to tell you about hangouts
yet. I am going to tell you about Pastor
Meyer's virtual office hours. If you are
wanting to speak to the pastor, you can
do that by setting up a virtual office
hour appointment and you can just email
Patrice at living.live live and she will
set that appointment up for you. Also,
um if you're wanting to become a member
of Living Mana Church, just like you saw
today, we had somebody become a member
by profession of faith. And so, that is
one way that you can do that. If you
feel like you don't need to get
rebaptized and you just and you would
like to become a member of the Seventh
Day Adventist Church, you can do that
off of profession of faith or you can
transfer. Or if you are a 7th Day
Adventist member, you can transfer your
membership to Living Man Church. And the
third way is that you can get baptized.
You if you want to study more about what
Seventh Day Adventists believe from the
Bible, you can do that. And if you
decide you want to get baptized, you can
get baptized and Pastor Meyers will
baptize you. All three of those ways of
becoming a member, you can you can just
send an email to patrice
livingmana.live.
And so if that's if you're wanting to
become a member, those are the three
ways that you can do that. So now I want
to tell you all about Hangouts. Hangouts
um is a it's just just like what it
sounds like, hanging out with the Living
Mana Church family so we can continue to
get to know each other better and a fun
relaxed setting. So want you to check
out uh this video that tells you a
little bit more about Hangouts.
Hey guys, this is your hanger host Ayana
sending you love all the way from the
lovely island of Trinidad and Tobago.
And I want to extend a special
invitation to each and every one of you
to join us at Hangouts every other
Sunday where we break out into groups of
10 and have games, riveting questions,
and just some clean Christian fun. So
come join us every other Sunday at
Hangouts. Feel free to invite a friend
and invite another friend as well. See
you there.
That's great. And our next hangouts is
tomorrow. Uh that's Sunday, February
22nd at 6:30 p.m. Central Standard Time.
So, you want to make sure that you join
the hangout space on mighty network for
for updates so you can always know when
uh the hangouts is going to be
happening.
Loc volunteers, we need you. We need you
to volunteer. These are the areas that
we are needing help with. LMOC Kids has
put out an SOS on children's ministry
needs additional volunteers to support
our growing group of little ones. If you
have a heart for teaching, serving, or
simply helping create a safe, joyful
space for our kids, this is a great
place for you to plug in. If you're
ready to serve and want to learn more,
visit the service opportunity section on
Mighty Networks. Every hand makes a
difference and there's a place prepared
for you.
Also want to tell you about our digital
small groups. They are organized um are
or sorry digital small groups are
designed to help you grow, connect and
find real community from from wherever
you are. They create safe supportive
space where you can learn, share and
walk through life with others who
understand your journey. One of those uh
small groups is STAR. Star is a support
group created to walk with you through
the journey of addiction recovery.
Whether you're just beginning or
continuing uh the path toward healing,
you are not alone. This is a safe uh
judgment-free space to share, grow, and
rebuild one step at a time. Star meets
Thursdays at 7:30 p.m. Central time. And
it um it s okay. and um its sessions are
open to everyone seeking support,
encouragement and real connection. Come
as you are. Hope lives here. So that is
STAR. Also want you to know about mental
health Monday. That's a program that I
uh co-host with Dr. Ricardo White. And
we are back. Last week we took a break
um where we just paused our our men's uh
mental health series but we will be back
this Monday continuing that topic. So
you do not want to miss uh mental health
Mondays. You know women you are invited
as well. We want you all to know how to
take care of the men in your life their
mental health or care for them or just
to have information on the things that
they go through um so that you can be
sensitive to that. So definitely men
please show up. It's about your mental
health but women show up as well so you
can know how to support the men um in
your life. Want to also remind you guys
about weight training. Uh weight
training is only at LMC. If you've been
hearing about Adam Patel's amazing
classes for El Moses and you are have
caught the buzz about Pastor Meyers
weight training, here's the truth. This
is one of the most transformative
trainings you'll find anywhere and it's
available exclusively through LMLC. The
full series is still accessible on our
YouTube playlist featuring powerful
guest teachers who brought their own
depth of fire. That's Adam Patel, Dakota
Day, Lwami Richardson, and Calvin Kim.
This isn't generic evangelism uh
content. This is Elamosi crafted
spiritual training designed to teach you
how to share your faith faith with
others and with clarity. So if you want
to check that out, it is the playlist is
on our LMOC
uh YouTube channel. Also want to tell
you guys about Seven Loaves and and Fish
Fishers. Seven Loaves and Fishers of
Men. Seven Loaves and Fishers of Men is
more than a group. It's a brotherhood.
It's more than a men's group, I should
say. This men's ministry uh group is led
by a team of incredible men who are
committed to growing in Christ serving
with purpose and strengthening one
another through accountability,
prayer, and real conversation. Together,
uh these brothers are building a space
where men can be where I'm sorry, where
men can be sharpened, uh supported, and
spiritually fed. Whether it's studying
the word, serving the community, or
simply showing up for one another, this
ministry is dedicated to raising up men
and lead with integrity, courage, and
compassion. And you can see there where
they meet on Tuesdays at 7:30 Central um
Standard Time. There's an email there
that you can um if you are um not in
America, you can send an email there to
the leadership and if you're wanting
more information and if you um have
signed up to get text alerts, you can
text men to that 855 number and you can
get information there if you're wanting
to be a part of the men's ministry.
Also, just want to remind you guys about
Alamos Global U. Almost global. This is
where we're able to go around the world
currently in si I'm sorry I was going to
say five seven different languages um of
the world and so they take Pastor
Meyer's uh sermons and it can actually
take anything any content that we
produce here at Living Mana Church and
it can take that content and turn it
into the seven different languages that
we currently have available to us. And
so I want to show you what that looks
like at this time.
Fantasma
Gloria
Moes Gloria
Gloria.
Gloria Jesus Magnific.
glorification.
We are just thankful to have that
technology to be able to translate and
currently as I've said in seven
different languages, we want to continue
to grow um in the languages that we're
able to go into all the world with. And
so if you would like to support uh that
aspect of Living Mana Church and other
aspects of um the church ministry, I
just want to share with you how you can
continue to give or start giving to
support what Living Mana Church is
doing. And you can do that by going to
Adventistgiving.org.
There you would put in living mana
church and a virtual tithe envelope
would um would would come would fall
down and you can see the envelope
categories there. You can give your
tithe and your tithe supports the
northeastern conference. Living matter
church is a member of the northeastern
conference. You can see there the local
church budget. That is where um those
funds stay with Living Mana Church and
we're able to uh do all the things that
Living Mana Church does which is a lot
and it needs uh the support from you
financially if you'd like to give and to
support our local church budget. It
helps uh to be able to support the
employees that we have um part-time that
are helping us with Living Managed
Church. It help us. It helps us with all
the resources that we need to be able uh
to do uh live broadcast like this every
week with the cameras, computers, the
lighting, the technology that we use to
be able to produce good quality
programming uh that can go into all the
world and to witness for Jesus. And so
the local church budget uh when you give
there that helps to that helps our
living mana church again do all the
things that it does. It also helps when
you give to the benevolence fund. That
helps us to be able to help others who
are in need and is requesting help from
our church to be able to help them. And
there you can go to um
adventistgiving.org and just view that
tithe envelope to see where you would
like to give to be able to support. Now,
if you're not wanting to give online,
but you would like to send in a check
and to be able to give that way, there's
the address on your screen that you can
use to be able to mail your support into
Living Mana Church. Please just write on
a little note what where you would like
your funds to go to. What is for tithe?
What's for offering? If there is a
specific area in Living Man Church that
you would like to support, please let us
know.
We just want to say thank you uh to all
of you for supporting Living Mana Church
in all the many ways. You show up every
week. You pray for Living Mana Church.
You share on your social media uh to let
people know that inviting them to
church. You share the videos. And so we
just want to say thank you. Um it really
helps be everything that you're
everything that you do by showing up by
praying by talking about it with friends
and family. that is very helpful in
allowing people to know that Living Mana
Church is here. Um, and it's here for
you and to and to bless you by God's
grace. And we just want to say thank you
to you again and thank you to God for
just giving us this space. And it's
almost four years. We're so thankful in
April it'll be four years that Living
Man Church has been here and we just
want to continue to grow in God's grace.
And so I would like to um ask you to bow
your heads with me as we pray and just
thank God for everything that uh he has
done for this church and will continue
to do for living mana church. So please
bow your heads with me as we pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, thank you for
this Sabbath. Lord, thank you for this
opportunity to just witness to the whole
world about your goodness and how
amazing you are, Lord. Lord, I just want
to especially thank you for the photo
the photo theology suite. It's been a
blessing to me. I know it's been a
blessing to so many um who have used it.
And I just pray that you will continue
uh to just take this app even deeper
into the hearts and souls of those who
are using it. Lord, let it just spread
uh so wide because we all need to go
deeper into our Bible study. Lord, we
need to take more time uh with that and
this app definitely helps us with that.
Lord, I want to pray over everyone who
is viewing. Lord, I pray over uh their
specific needs in the areas that they
are needing. Lord, the marriages that
are needing help. Lord, I pray over the
I pray over them. those who are going
through a health journey right now,
Lord, and they are just needing your
healing power. Lord, I pray that you
will bring healing to them. Lord, I pray
for all the family issues and things
that people are going through that their
personal issues, Lord, just uh give them
wisdom and guide them on how to deal
with those issues, Lord, that are so
sensitive. And Lord, finances, that is a
big one for so many um all around the
world, Lord. And so I just pray that you
will provide the needs for those who are
hurting and and just dealing with
financial issues at this time. Lord, I
lift up Pastor Meyers to you and just
asking that uh the Holy Spirit, the
sermon and the message that you have put
on his heart that it will be delivered
today in such a powerful way that it
will touch all of our hearts and that we
will leave church today changed people
and we will want to share it with the
world. Lord, I ask all these things in
Jesus name. Amen.
I
don't know.
Heat. Heat.
God of creation
there at the start before the beginning
of time
with no point of reference.
He spoke to the dark and fleshed out the
wonder of light.
And as you speak,
100 billion galaxies are born.
In the vapor of your breath, the planets
fall form.
If the stars were made to worship, so
will I.
I can see your hand in everything you've
done.
Every burning star a signal fire of
grace.
If creation sings your praises, so will
I.
So will I.
God of your promise.
You don't speak in vain. No sinable
empty voice.
For once you have spoken.
All nature and science follow the sound
of your voice.
And as you speak,
a h 100 billion creatures catch your
breath.
>> Evolving in pursuit of what you say.
If it all reveals your nature, so will
I.
So will I.
So we
if the stars were made to worship, so
will I.
If the mountains were made to worship,
so will I.
If the oceans royal praises, so will I.
For if everything exists to lift you
high, so will I.
The wind goes where you send it, so will
I.
Oh,
if the rocks cry out in silence, so will
I.
If the song of all our praise is still
for shine,
then we'll sing again a h 100 billion
times.
Oh.
God of salvation.
You chased up my heart through all of my
failure and pride
on a hill. You ced
the light of the world abandoned in
darkness to die.
And as you speak,
>> a 100 million failings disappear.
Where you lost your life so I could find
me here.
>> If you left the grave behind you, so
will I.
I can see a heart in everything you've
done.
>> Every part design and a work of our
call.
If you're glad you chose surrender, so
will I.
>> I can see your heart 8 billion different
ways.
Every preious one, the child you die to
save.
If you gave your life to love them, so
will I.
Like you would again 100 billion times.
What measure could amount to your
desire?
You're the one who never leave the one
behind.
>> You're the one who never leave the one
Here at Living Mana, we bear each
other's burdens. When you need support
or prayer, when you're feeling
discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face life struggles
alone.
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
grace to help in our time of need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those who are crushed in
spirit.
Amen. Amen. Greetings, Loc family,
friends, visitors, saints of the most
high God. I am brother Terry. This is my
lovely bride Amra. We're celebrating our
eighth anniversary, by the way, y'all.
And
>> yes, we are.
>> Thank God for that. But we want to say
welcome to you. Welcome to another
edition of Living Manners Prayer and
Praise Time. You know, it was late on my
heart to put a a greeting in the chat
earlier that listen, we are experiencing
the presence and power of God here in
such a very special way. I know y'all
can say amen, saints. See you shouting
out in church. Brother Clint, see you in
the chat there. Um, who was it that just
said, "I need prayer support." Noah,
Noah, praying for you. You can get it
here. Love and prayer support all the
time. Um, I won't be long with you today
because we have some really powerful
stuff we want to share with you in the
praise report department. All right. So,
uh, just want to sweep down the whole
list, the whole family, everybody. Love
y'all. Okay. Won't do a roll call today.
There's one special shout out I do want
to do today.
Sister Pauline's granddaughter, Micaia,
who's turning 11 years old today.
Micaia, this is your birthday.
>> We love you, young lady. We've been
praying for you every day, believe me.
And we thank God for you are special.
God has a plan for your young, special,
precious lives. You keep on holding on
and being strong, young lady. And so,
we're just celebrating you. Ah, we see
the anniversary shout outs in the chat.
Thank y'all for wishing us a happy
anniversary. Listen, I think me and me
me and Amber met eight years ago. A
little over eight years ago.
>> Four months.
>> Eight years in about five minutes. Look,
we met and Nicole, you know that that
amazing timeline, right? We met and I
think about 20 minutes later we're
engaged and about two days later we're
married, right? Something like that. No,
I'm just kidding. Not that fast. But God
>> was pretty fast.
God did an amazing thing and it is the
hand of God and everything that we have
all that we are is ours only because God
is so good and amazing. So last week
when pastor Nante was talking about love
doing Sabbath school um pastor said
instead of worrying about who God has
for you get with God and let God make
you the person that somebody else needs
you to be. Amen. And uh I thank God for
keeping me where he kept me for so long
working on me. He didn't give up on me.
He's not giving up on you. And this is
the reward of all those tears and all
those prayers and all that labor and
God's faithfulness. So, I thank God for
you, my love. You uh you are something
else. You're a blessing to me. And so,
>> well, I thank God for you. And you know,
every time we get into some spirited
fellowship, I just remind him I'm 25
years of answer prayer,
>> okay? and you only have to deal with me
every day until the day you die.
>> Had to bring that up, right? So, uh
it's beautiful. I thank God for it. Uh
it's a blessing. And so, yeah, men out
there, uh stay strong, stay faithful,
stay true. And what I'm going to tell
you, listen, I got to say one more thing
and I'm gonna hand it over to Amra.
The photo theology spiritual educational
suite. Let me tell you, next level. This
software that Professor X has put
together is just absolutely amazing. I
mean, and I'm talking about our pastor.
I call him Professor X because God is
doing amazing
supernatural things in that mind. And
and I thank you uh first lady for being
such an incredible support for him and
uh being there for him and just such a
compliment to that amazing gift and your
amazing gift. So y'all just a y'all just
a ball of fire together. So thank God
for y'all. Certainly an example to us.
But I want to pray about the want us to
pray about the photo theology app,
right? The users, the members, and as
they mentioned this morning, tech
support because you know that once a
bunch of people start getting on that
thing and and and and just all over the
place exploring, everybody's got a
different profile and a different way
they study and using all of those
amazing features. I mean, 38 tabs in the
home. uh uh tab alone, 38 tabs in the
main suite. And inside of each of those
38 tabs, you see it. Get in there and
move around, navigate, see what you got.
And um hundreds of features so you can
just tailor make your study uh to suit
you and the way you think and the way
you learn and the way you grow. It is
I'm telling you,
I don't have any words. So, Professor X,
my brother, love you and uh admire you.
Thank God. and truly a teacher, truly a
vessel that God has used to bring
something. I mean, absolutely
revolutionary. And so, uh, make the most
of it, saints. Get in there. Get in
there. Get in there. All right. Yeah.
Yeah. Third angel. He That's Professor X
for sure. Y'all know that. So,
>> praise my beloved.
>> All right. Well,
>> before I begin, just a couple
announcements. If you have a prayer
request or a praise report that you
would like to submit, please send an
email to pray
living mana.urch
and we have prayer warriors that will
pray over your prayer requests all
through the week and then any prayers
reports I can share here on the
broadcast.
We are always looking for new members to
join our prayer team. So if you would
like to join this community, it is an
amazing one to be a part of. Also,
please send an email to pray at living
mana.urch.
If you need a special ops team, that is
a group of people that will be praying
throughout the week daily. for detailed
prayer for yourself or a loved one,
please send an email to spec ops
living.urch.
If you need a midweek pickme up, please
join us every Wednesday for Power
Wednesday. That is at 4:30 p.m. Pacific
Standard Time, 7:30 Eastern Standard
Time. And it is always a great way to
connect with other people in the church.
We have devotionals, we have
testimonials, and we also have uh just
fellowship and prayer. It's awesome.
Following that is the power line, and
that is live on YouTube every week.
That's at 6:00 p.m. Pacific Standard
Time, 900 p.m. Eastern Standard Time.
And that is live prayer, so anyone can
put it in the chat and it will be prayed
for live.
So those are the announcements I have.
>> Amen.
>> All right. Starting off the praise
reports, we have one from Robert E.
Plant. The results of my nerve
conduction study came back normal.
Though carpal tunnel and cubital for
forearm tunnel have not been ruled out.
I praise God for this report.
>> Amen. Amen. Praise God. Elder Robert,
love you. Love you, brother.
>> Praise God. from Laura Powell. Thank you
so much, saints, for praying for us
yesterday. We're praising God for all
things while still recovering from
bronchitis, pneumonia, and I'm much
better now. I was prepping for a
Revelation Bible study last night, but
when I turned on my computer yesterday
morning, Word disappeared along with all
my documents that I had prepared for all
of the Bible studies, not just last
night's. Our internet was hardly working
yesterday, too. and we had to turn it
off and back on several times to get it
to work, which was intermittent at best.
We also had planned to have a guest
pastor join us by Zoom. The Lord guided
us and what to do as I was just trying
everything I knew to do to get word back
and my documents and we finally got it.
The meeting started with the pastor and
went very well. Praise God. Then the
internet quit again just after he
finished. I was able to transfer
internet by using my phone and we were
able to finish our Bible study. Praise
God. Isn't that a marvelous answer to
prayer? Thank you so much. God is so
good. He is getting his message out no
matter what.
>> Amen. And greetings to you, Tom and
Laura. We love you. Laura is the living
man of war yet. And and Laura, baby, we
call her affectionately. And we love you
and we miss you here. Thank you. Keep on
letting the Lord use you the way he has
been, Sister Laura.
>> Amen. from Ramona Baddy. Praise report.
Mikuel and Marilyn, my twin grandsons,
mom and grandmother are okay. Marilyn
left the hospital a few days ago and
Mikuel is being released today. She's
breathing on her own now. Thanks to my
entire Locosc family for every single
prayer. Stana's surgery went well and
she's recovering speedily. Thank you
all. Prayer changes things.
>> Amen.
>> From Kimberly. Hallelujah. The debt is
paid. Miraculously, I had a refund. The
miracle refund was more than enough to
pay the debt. God is so good. Jehovah
Gyra always takes care of me. Did
anybody even have time to say amen
before God stepped in? And a bunch of
fire emojis. Look at our God.
>> Oh, that was those were my words at the
end because I reported her. That was
>> Oh, that was you.
>> Yeah. From the social chat. Kimberly
emailed us in the morning. Then about
2:00
she thanked us for praying for her and
then maybe about an hour or two later,
God had come through for her. It was
like really quickly. So Kimberly, love
you and so glad to hear that God's
moving in your life that way. That's
amazing.
>> All right, Olivia Torres, here's her
prayer request. Please pray for my
property tax exemption homestead. They
have been dragging out the process. I
always get the same response. It is
pending. The property tax here in Texas
is unbelievable. That's what we've
heard. Please pray with me that I will
get a response from the Hidalgo
appraisal district after numerous phone
calls. I just sent them an email to
follow up as well today. Yes, things are
just getting out of hand. Those who are
honest in their taxes are the ones who
need to go through this. Lord have
mercy.
>> And the praise report. I requested a
prayer for my property tax homestead
exemption. Great is his faithfulness.
The Hidalgo appraisal district sent me
an email notifying me of the approval.
What a burden lifted from my shoulder.
This should this could not be possible
without your intercessory prayer on my
behalf and his divine interventions.
Thank you so much. Hallelujah. Amen.
Lastly, my autoimmune flare up not only
affects my endurance but also my
mobility to some extent. Yes, I have a
specialist on board. you name it. I will
need to set up to see my cardiologist
and pulmonologist if this persists. God
is a way of sending signals to my body
when it's time. And I know he will give
me the discernment when needed. Overall,
it is under control and manageable. I
just need to slow down and rest, take my
medications. Praise God for his
unceasing prayers. For your unceasing
prayers, blessings to you all. Have a
blessed preparation day. And quickly
from the chat,
Gingerella had a praise report.
Gingerella 007, a dear friend struggling
with substance abuse for decades has
informed us today that she is finally
free from the crippling addiction that
robbed her dignity and future. God is
good.
And lastly, from Gary Benson, happy
Sabbath, everyone. Thank you for the
shout out last week. Michaela is home
from the hospital.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Now,
we have a special praise report guest.
>> Buckle up.
>> Buckle up. It is our own church
secretary, Patrice Delisser, as she
comes on board member.
>> Yes.
But Patrice has experienced quite the
journey and she is coming on to share
a pretty amazing praise report.
>> Amen. Amen.
All right, Patrice, let him use you.
There she is.
>> There she is. Hello, Patrice.
>> Oh, we can't hear you.
>> You're pulling a T. She pulled a Terry.
We can't hear you.
>> No,
>> I'm not muted.
>> Oh, there you are.
>> There you are. There you are.
>> There you are.
>> It's not
>> uh You're good.
>> We have a scene. We hear you now.
>> We have a scene in in the uh tech team.
It's um it's a software. It's an inside
joke. So,
>> um I know the tech team, they got it.
They got it. They got it. So anyway,
happy Sabbath everybody. It is so great
to uh to be here. I never thought I
would be here to be honest with you. Um
but yet I am. Um I want to give a big
special shout out to
um two individuals, actually three that
are actually part of this testimony. And
if Colin if I don't know if it's
possible if we can do a side by side the
um view let's do that. If not I will
continue.
Oh boy. Well when brother Terry said uh
buckle up that's an understatement
for the there's actually a two-part but
the first part of it I I cannot share um
right now. Um, but at some point I'll be
able to share that part because it
actually intersects with what I'm about
to share with you. Now,
last week
on Sunday,
um, I have to give you context and give
you the background of exactly where this
story is about to go. So, currently
where I live, it is Thank you, Colin.
Thank you so much. Currently where I
live um on the property that I live on
is three properties. It's the house
there's a cottage right behind the house
and then about 50 feet a little over 50
feet away is a double garage with an
apartment on top of the garage. So
there's an apartment there. Cottage
behind uh the main house and uh the
house is where my family lives. There is
a uh woman that lives right behind us.
Literally our cottage, her cottage
almost butt butts up against the house.
And then as I said between 50 and about
50 a little over 50 feet away is the
double garage with the above garage
apartment.
I have to give you that context and
layout because it's it's it is important
for what I'm about to share.
>> So
>> amen.
Last week
about five o'clock, a little before five
o'clock,
my daughter came home from work. One of
my daughters came home from from work
and she came in the house to tell me
that
she heard some
someone yelling like they were really in
pain.
But she came in the house. She said, you
know, I don't know where it's coming
from and I'm not going to get involved
because I don't know where it's coming
from. So, she came to the house and
shortly
after she said that, probably within
about 15 minutes or so,
she was by the window and said, "Um,
there police here with guns
and they're pointing towards
the double garage."
And I proceeded to look out the window
to find that what she said was actually
true. They were
uh trained officers with rifles with
scopes
and pointing in that direction. And when
I looked out it was three. And as I'm
looking at three, then another patrol
car pulls up with guns out and loaded
and pointed towards that direction.
I proceeded to tell everybody, "Go
upstairs. Go upstairs now because
everybody is essentially on the first
floor and whatever is about to happen,
bullets don't have a a a specific when
when shots are being fired, it's going
to go everywhere."
>> And so
we proceeded to go upstairs
and we're looking out and now there more
police that are coming.
At some point,
the neighbor behind me who's in the
cottage,
everybody is frantic. My son is about to
go downstairs and say, "I'm going to go
outside and see and see what's going
on." Which I immediately yelled, "You
cannot go outside. You in particular
can't go outside and I'll just leave
that there. You stay up here. I'll go."
So, as I'm looking out to see exactly
what's happening, but I'm not sure
what's going on. I can't even I can't
reach my husband because my husband is
out of state and my cell phone is
downstairs and I can't even get a down
go reach for my phone and get to my
phone because to be honest with you, I
was terrified because if it starts, I
don't know what's about to happen.
>> Yeah. So
about a couple seconds later, all this
is happening in real time, in rapid
time. This is not a This is not This is
not a movie. This is literally happening
in real life. And I'm am petrified. I'm
petrified for my kids. I'm petrified for
my neighbors. I don't know what's
happening. What is going on?
So, I finally see
my cottage neighbor. She had just pulled
up because she was out. She was at work.
Her son, who was 18 years old, he was at
at her house at the cottage.
And when I see her and she's talking to
the state police, I now go out and feel
a little more comfortable to go out. And
I'm as I'm going out the door, I say to
her, "Hey, um I'm not saying names for a
reason, just protecting their
anonymity." I said, "Hey, what's
happening? What's going on?" And she
says,
"Our neighbor just shot himself.
He had shot himself.
And somehow the reason why the police
there were there and I gave you the
layout for a reason
because he did it in his in his
apartment.
He was able to make his way
50 ft out of his house
to their front door
where he was covered in blood.
The 18-year-old
went to the door to find the neighbor
literally out through the glass.
He had shot himself in the head.
>> He was petrified and called his mother.
Didn't open the door cuz he didn't know
what was happening. All he said was,
"Did someone shoot you?" And he said the
best that he could acknowledge was yes.
And he didn't open the door because we
didn't know he didn't know what was
happening. And when his mother came to
the she was four four minutes away from
where we live and when he told her what
was happening she came locked and loaded
as well.
All this is happening in real time in a
matter of seconds and even minutes.
They are we are now a crime scene and
now we are being told by the police we
have got to clear we have got to search
your house because they could possibly
have made their way in your house.
So now we are petrified.
Everybody is out. It is ice cold.
There's snow everywhere.
And
they now have to come through and scope
through the house where we are.
It is a chaotic, horrific scene.
The paramedics finally came
and when they got here, didn't realize
cuz I didn't know where he was. He was
literally in my peripheral view and they
were attending to him on the ground.
When they moved him out,
they moved him out. I was able to
contact my husband and tell him what was
going on.
But I want to pause here for a second
because
even in that God is doing something
because there's no way in the world that
you can make your way from that type of
self-inflicted injury
50 plus feet away
to make it to the door.
In the meantime,
Michelle, as I said, sorry, I'm almost
almost said her name, but you don't know
her last name. She actually made her
way. And when she got there and got in
front of the door,
she was able to now at this point,
she was able to hold his hands.
She was able to hold his hands.
and
she was able to hold his hands and
ask him, "Did he know Jesus?"
And he said to her, he was still able to
communicate with her and said,
"I need Jesus.
I need Jesus."
While she's holding his bloody hands,
she says to him,
"He's here and he loves you. And if you
ask him into your heart, he will come
in."
To which he says, "I need him.
>> I need him." And she says, "Please pray
this prayer with me,
a prayer of acceptance of Christ in your
life.
and he was able to do so
before he collapsed.
The paramedics worked on him
and whisked him away.
Later on that evening, there's so many
things that's happening.
But before I get there, after he's
whisked away, I immediately,
she's a believer, I'm a believer.
And we began to pray and I said, 'I know
what I'm going to do. I'm calling my
brother. And I called and I sent a
message to Terry.
>> I said, Terry, this is what's happening.
We need to pray.
It's funny because
I always thought to myself, one day,
maybe I'll join the sniper team, prayer
sniper team. But never in my wildest
dreams thought that this would be
something that I was going to be thrust
into. Uh never. You know they say truth
is stranger than fiction. It is.
So
Terry
Amra I sent a message to sister Shaunine
and we began to to start praying.
My other daughter Shelby
who was at a rise in Finland last year,
she contacted her prayer group in
Finland
immediately
and told them what was happening and
told them that we need to start praying.
I can give you his name. His name is
Dan.
We need to pray for Dan.
So, as we're praying for Dan, Terry's
praying, Amber's praying, Sister Shaun's
praying, and I am praying,
and my neighbor is also praying.
We're still a crime scene for hours
because they don't know. They had gone
through my house. There's nobody here.
And it wasn't until close to midnight
that they said it was all clear and they
left the property.
We have no idea what is going on. But
anyway, in short, I'm trying to shorten
this, but it's I need you to really get
the context of what we have all what
we've all been through. And I reason why
I want Terry and Amber side by side in
terms of the view because they're
intricral part of this testimony. And
sister Sha need, if she were here, she'd
be on screen, too.
>> Amen. So my other daughter Lauren,
she's also praying and she when she's is
able to we able to leave the property to
go to her place,
she sends me a message and she says,
"Mom, look outside."
She said, "Mom, it's snowing."
And I said, "Yeah, it is." And she went
straight to Isaiah chapter one. Though
your sins be as scarlet, they shall be
as white as snow.
>> Amen.
>> She said, "Mom,
God's going to do something."
>> She said, "I see." She said, "I know. I
don't know how. I don't know why. I
don't know. I don't know anything, but
his sins are forgiven
and he I believe he's in the kingdom.
That his he's going to be in the
kingdom." And I said, "Listen, if God
can do that for the thief on the cross,
I don't know anything about his
background, but if he could do it for
the thief on the cross, he could do it
for anybody. So, I'm not saying he can't
do it and I'm saying he won't do it. I'm
believing with you."
So, we continued to pray
and
I was a we were able later on to
contact. He lived alone, so he's not
married. There's no children. And so we
were trying to reach his parents.
So we were able to reach his parents
and we're able to contact the parents
and we ended up talking to his dad who
they are just traumatized. The family is
traumatized.
>> They never saw any they never saw this
coming. We they all they kept saying was
we we missed the signs.
We missed the signs.
So Dan had two pets, two dogs, um, and
one of them was able to when the police
had come before they took Dan away had
got out, but he was out, but he's older,
kind of older. And I share that for a
reason because we end up taking him in.
We have a little Yorkie who thinks he's
a German Shepherd and he's not, but
um we cared for him and
we just felt like these were these were
these were Dan's kids and we wanted to
take care of them. So
every update I would get, I would text
now Dan's sniper team,
brother Terry,
Sister Shaine.
But I was able to talk with Dan's
father. I said, "Listen,
we are praying for your son and please
know we're also praying for you." And I
said, "If you don't mind," I said, "we
are calling his name out all over the
world." I said my daughter this she's
contacted her friends in Finland and we
are praying for him.
>> It's so much I'm trying my best to keep
myself together. So,
>> Amen.
>> With every update,
we didn't know what was happening. But
when I talked to him that night, he said
that he was in surgery.
And I said, "He's in surgery." In my my
mind think he's in surgery.
So, okay, he's in surgery.
And all I they're telling them is he's
stable
>> right now. He's holding up in the
surgery.
And I said, "Okay." I said, "Do me a
favor.
It doesn't matter. anytime, day or
night, call or text me. Whatever update
you give me, I immediately am going to
give it to the sniper team. And I did.
>> Amen.
>> And they immediately started praying.
So with that prayer,
they would go right in.
The next day, this is now Monday. He's
in ICU. He's still alive. Heavy
sedation.
>> Amen.
I see his brother.
I meet his brother. There's only two of
them. And he meet I meet him here in the
property and he collapses in my arms.
>> He is not a belie at all. And I said
asked him if he didn't mind if I prayed
with him and he said, "I don't mind." He
said, "I don't believe God. I don't
believe in God, but you know, if you
want to pray, that's, you know, go
ahead." And I did. and he just cried in
my arms.
>> He was on his way back to the hospital.
They're taking turns. The parents are
distraught. His mom, their their mom and
and the dad is just so distraught.
But he's now we go into Tuesday and I'm
giving the update. He's still here.
Brother Terry can tell you he's still
here.
>> Amen.
Wednesday,
Dan's dad gives me a message. They
weaned him a little bit off of the
sedation to see if he had any cognitive
function at all.
And he was able to move a little bit of
his limbs.
And once they saw that, they put him
back under again.
what Thursday
they were able to
take him off a little bit more to see if
he had any additional commands he could
follow
and he had more that he could do with
the right side was a little stronger
than the left side that's Thursday
there's so many details in there between
there that I don't have time to do it
I'm just giving you
When I saw his dad yesterday,
he said that they had taken him off.
They were weaning him off the breathing
apparatus
that he was still here. Okay. Sent the
update one more one more time. All
right, sniper team. This is what he did.
I copied and paste. I didn't even write
it. I would just copy what he sent me
the text and put it right in there.
Said, "Dan, update from Dan's dad. Here
it is. Let's go."
>> Amen.
Now I'm being now at this point Terry's
already asked me if I would come and
share the testimony we've got so far and
I said
absolutely
but the enemy tried to come in yesterday
for a testimony I can't share right now
but it was it was pretty bad
>> and Terry said the enemy doesn't want
you to share it and I responded back to
him
Revelation 12:11 and they overcame him
by the blood of the lamb and the word of
their testimony. I said, I'm going to
tell this testimony.
>> Amen.
>> So, so Terry and Amra and Sister
Shaunine don't don't know this part.
They're going to hear this for the first
time.
Dan's father called me this morning
and this is what he said.
First, he wanted to say thank you to the
prayer team.
He wanted to thank Terry Ammer and
Sister Shaine. And I'm going to let
Shelby know for her prayers and the
prayer group in Finland.
How appreciative that he is for your
prayers over his son because he wasn't a
believer, but he has seen God do
something and now he has accepted Jesus.
Hallelujah.
>> But this morning
he also said and shared this testimony.
And I want you to remember it is
Sabbath.
He said the breathing tube has been
removed.
All machines are removed.
He is talking.
He is moving all of his limbs.
His left side is a little weak, but the
right side is strong.
They have him on a
soft diet.
>> He is able to eat soft food,
yogurts, things of that night. That way,
he wants a cheese steak, but the doctors
told him, "You can't have a cheese
steak."
>> Yeah. Yeah.
He remembers phone numbers.
>> Wow.
>> And
he told them
what he did.
And this family is getting healing
and help.
>> Praise God.
>> Hallelujah.
>> There's so much more.
Yes,
>> here's an extra gift.
>> And this is for brother Terry.
I took it upon myself to ask Dan's dad
if he wouldn't mind
sharing with the men's group when they
are ready.
>> And to which he said, "Yes, would be
glad to do so."
>> Praise God. So, Brother Terry, he said,
"Whenever you are ready and whenever
they're ready and they're up to it, they
will be happy to connect with you and
have you uh greet them and bring him
into the men's group when he's ready.
They want to share the testimony of what
God is doing and what how you are such
an integral part along with Amar and
sister Shaunie and this other sniper
teams across the world in this
miraculous healing
>> because
God is doing something amazing
and And I really believe
there's no way a man who has done a
self-inflicted wound like this would
make it 50 feet.
>> That was his guardian angel taking him
to a place because God had put everybody
in place. There's no way that a
neurosurgeon
that would have been on call that night
at the hospital was already in place.
Everybody was in place for something we
didn't know and we was preparing for.
So let this testimony be what it is.
God is great and great
>> to be praised.
>> Yes, he is, Patrice.
>> Amen.
>> Yes, he is. Praise God for you. And I
know we we we knew it was worth taking
the time to hear how God
>> can step in in such a tragic moment like
that. And this is only half.
>> Stay tuned. There is another glorious
chapter. You guys haven't heard, but you
have been praying. So, thank God. And
and saints, I part of me wants to say
I'm sorry because we don't usually take
up this much time. We're getting ready
for the word of God. But listen, that is
part of the word of God, is it not? Is
that not God moving? That was an amazing
>> and if he done it for Dan, he will do it
for you. Uh we still need to go to the
throne of grace and sorry for taking up
so much time, but may God encourage your
heart, lift your spirits, believe that
he's hearing and answering your prayers.
Sister Barbara from the Fab 7 is going
to come and she's going to introduce a
prayer from all the way halfway around
the world in Africa. Sister Shalala is
going to pray for us today briefly and
we're going to thank God for the word
that's coming forth. Sister Barbara, we
love you. Thank you for waiting on us
and being so There's my beautiful sister
Barbara. Hallelujah.
>> Hi, Barbara.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Happy Sabbath all. I love praise
reports. They're my favorite part. And
and that praise report was a was just
wanted to pull my heart out. And and
it's one of those cases where you say,
"But Christ
And that's it. So, I'm not going to go
into our scripture
today because of the time,
but um our scripture was Ephesians 6:18.
So, look it up yourself in the in the
photo theology Bible and and um the
prayer I'm just going to read the prayer
requests and then
>> and and I'm going to go really quickly
with it and then we're going to bring
sister Chalala on video um all the way
from Zambia
um and she will do the prayer. So, we
are saying a prayer for Sister Ammer and
and Terry's birthday.
And Nicole is asking us
to pray for the steroids that the doctor
prescribed for her dad that they will
work and restore his hearing in his
right ear.
And Reed WLR
is asking us to pray that for the church
to pray for his wife's upcoming travel.
And um he has a reward that's only a
hurdle away
and he's losing his hearing now first in
his left ear.
And
um he knows that healing is in the
Lord's hands.
And si sister Sister Sheila is asking us
to pray for Stephanie Rose who is in the
valley of decision on keeping the
Sabbath.
She believes it's true. Um, but she's
tied to her Sunday church. And Llaya
Peterson is requesting prayer that their
heat pump, which
has not been working, will be fixed this
week. And though it's likely to be
expensive, she's praying that it will be
something that they can afford.
And she's asking to give them the faith
that the Lord will provide.
And then Gingerella 007
is requesting prayer for a friend,
sorry,
who needs $20,000 to cover medical
expenses for a delicate condition
and may his GoFundMe
um may he get many returns on that and
he be able to receive all the treatment
needed
and bless those who donate. She's also
requesting for prayer for all the
ministries including Pastor Meyers who
wield the word of God globally.
And she's asking for prayer for crushing
initable
headaches and people who for people who
suffer from migraines. She said it's
very tough but they still trust the
Lord.
and Veronica Foster Kitten uh 298 is
praying is asking for prayer for her
husband um that he will take the time to
do the photo theology with her
and she says I have a tendency to want
to do things on my own and Ponzi Pansy
is asking for to please pray for his
family and especially his son Wanza and
friend Grace Pray
and I am
asking for prayer for all those who are
learning and navigating the photo
theology suite that all may use this
tool to its fullest.
Thanks to the Lord for this tool and to
God be the glory. Also prayer for the
technology and the live stream and be
with the tech team and all the plates
that they have spinning. And Jamie A5382
is asking us to pray for Dela who is
unhoused and contact with her has been
lost.
And Renee Baytops 146 is is asking for
prayer for her family and her son Tyrus
who needs prayer for mental health and
prayer for her needing God and leading
and direction. and she is in need of a
place for her and her two grandsons to
move to.
And we continue to pray for Eden's full
recovery. Give her your comfort, your
peace, and your hope. And after that
testimony, we are praying for Dan's
recovery. And we are praying for pastor
and today's message. So now we'll go to
Chalalala in Zambia her video and for
prayer for these in the prayer request.
Living mana family good morning. I pray
the Lord is watching over you keeping
you and protecting you. Happy Sabbath.
Happy Sabbath.
This is from Zambia. I pray today that
we are enjoying the wonderful Sabbath
that the Lord has given us. This is the
day he has given us. We will rejoice and
be glad in it. So I'm going to pray with
you in Jesus mighty name. Let us pray.
Our father who art in heaven, glory,
honor and majesty belongs to you. Who
alone is mighty, great in praises, doing
wonders. We bless your holy name. We
thank you for bringing us together on
this wonderful Sabbath to worship you,
to exalt your name, to give you praise
for you are deserving of it, Jehovah.
Aba Father, I pray that everyone who's
tuned in today, forgive us our
shortcomings. Cleanse us of all our
unrighteousness. Give us clean hearts.
Purify our hearts and our minds. Jehovah
I pray father in Jesus name any person
today who's tuned in with any form of
affliction dear God I pray that by the
mighty name of Jesus let every form of
affliction be loosed in Jesus' name I
pray for everyone who is in interceding
for a family member for healing father
God let them receive the healing in
Jesus name everyone who's tuned in today
they are afflicted with disease is
almighty God. I pray that let them
receive healing by the mighty hand of
our Lord Jesus Christ. I pray for us
today who are tuned in. Give us the
spirit of wisdom, of knowledge, and of
understanding that as the message shall
be preached, Father God, we shall not go
back the same. We shall be restored. We
shall be renewed in the power of the
Holy Spirit. Father God, you will
transform our hearts and our minds and
be brought in in in alignment with
Christ. I pray for your man's servant
today as he preaches the message of the
gospel that those who are seeking hope
today, they shall come to this stream.
You shall lead them and they shall find
hope. Everyone who's lo who's tuned in
today to listen to the word of God.
Father God, I pray that that hope be
restored. Almighty God, let healings be
given in Jesus' name. That you shall
empower every word spoken by him today.
That father God, healing, restoration,
grace, and favor shall be granted upon
us in Jesus' name. I pray, Father God,
that you shall sanctify us by the word
which shall be taught today because thy
word is truth. We thank you that you are
a good God, that you are a mighty father
who watches over us, who never leaves us
nor forsakes us. So thank you. I pray to
you Lord, be glorified, be exalted
because you are able to do exceedingly
abundantly more than we could ever ask
or imagine. In the blessed name of our
king and our Lord Jesus Christ, I anchor
this prayer. Amen. And amen. May the
Lord bless you, the Lord keep you. May
he make his face to shine upon you and
give you peace in Jesus name. Amen.
You were not hidden.
There's never been a moment. You were
forgotten.
You were not hopeless.
Though you have been broken, you're
innocent stolen.
I hear you whisper
underneath your breath.
I hear your sos.
Your sos.
I will send out an army to find you in
the middle of the darkest night is true.
I will rescue you.
There is no distance
that cannot be covered over and over.
You're not defenseless.
I'll be your shelter and I'll be your
armor.
I hear you whisper underneath
your breath.
I hear your sos
your s.
Yay.
Oh, and I will send out an army to find
you in the middle of the darkest
tonight. It's true. I will rescue you.
Oh, and I will never stop marching to
reach you. In the middle of the hardest
fight, it's true. I will rescue you.
Oh, I hear the whisper
underneath your breath.
I hear you whisper, "You have nothing
left."
Oh, and I will send out an army to find
you in the middle of the darkest night.
It's true. I will rescue you.
Oh, and I will never stop watching to
reach you in the middle of the heart. If
I true, I will resue you.
Oh, I will resue you.
Oh, I will rescue
you.
Oh,
I will rescue you.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Heat
up here.
Heat up here.
Heat
up here.
up
here.
Amen. Amen. Happy Sabbath everyone. Um
we want to welcome you to Living Mana
online church once again. We are getting
ready to get into the word of God. We're
getting ready to uh partake of the
living mana.
And um
if you are if you are ready and prepared
after
uh that that opening to hear the word of
God, please go ahead and
in the chat. Um, we're going to be
dealing with a very special
message today. Um, and that message
is entitled A Deep Sleep.
A deep sleep.
And so I want to invite you to uh pray
with me as we get ready to open the word
of God.
Heavenly Father,
Lord, we come before you today asking
that you would guide our thoughts, Lord.
As we open your word, I pray, Lord, that
you would please speak and that your
people will hear.
Thank you, Lord, for this message and
for what it will do in the hearts of
those who hear it. We pray his name.
Amen. Amen.
So once again everyone um we are going
to be addressing the the subject uh that
I've entitled a deep sleep and I want to
go to the screen.
Um we're going to be looking at we're
going to be beginning in Genesis
chapter 2
and verse 21. Genesis chapter 2
and verse
21,
the Bible says,
"And the Lord God caused a deep sleep to
fall upon Adam, and he slept,
and he took one of his ribs and closed
up the flesh instead thereof.
And the rib which the Lord God had taken
from man
made he a woman and he brought her unto
the man.
Now I am going to
uh simply mention
something right off the top here.
Um, and this is going to set the stage
for the entire message.
In Genesis 2 21 and 22, uh, the Bible
tells us that God
brought Adam into a deep sleep. He put
him into a deep sleep.
And this word uh this this this term a
deep sleep we must understand is not the
normal
type of sleep. Um the Hebrew word for
deep sleep here is tardama which means a
term or is a term that is often
associated with a divine
supernatural
slumber.
a state where human consciousness is
entirely
suspended.
It is not a natural sleep but an induced
state, a profound trance.
There is a lot in this verse
when when when God says that it is not
good for the man to be alone. I want you
to note what does not happen.
God does not say to Adam, "Adam, I need
you to solve this problem."
God does not say to Adam, "Adam, uh, I
need you to to create or to help create
a help meat for you. I need you to
assist
in the process." None of that happens.
God simply puts Adam into a deep sleep
and then God works. Adam does not even
witness the process.
There is a problem.
Adam goes to sleep and when he wakes up,
the problem
is solved.
And you guys, I want you to know that
this is the theme I'm going to build on.
And and we we might just stop the
message right here.
God put Adam into a deep sleep
and then performed what he needed to
perform.
It was like divine anesthesia. God put
Adam to sleep and performs the first
surgery. And within this this this
picture, we actually have a picture of
something so powerful, so amazing. But I
want to add to that picture before we
get to that point. Let's go to the book
of Genesis.
The book of Genesis chapter 15. In
Genesis chapter 15, Abraham
or Abram as the Bible calls him at that
point is is wondering about this promise
that God has laid out for him. Abraham,
you will have an heir.
Abraham is now old and he's wondering,
is this going to happen?
The Bible says in Genesis 15 verse 8 and
9, he said, 'Lord God, whereby shall I
know that I shall inherit it? Now, the
the it here is now talking about the
land. Earlier on in the chapter, he's
talking about the uh uh the the seed,
and now he's asking, "How will I know
that I will inherit the land?" And he's
talking about the promised land. And and
God says to him, "Take me a heer of
three years old, and a she goat of three
years old, and a ram of three years old,
and a turtle dove, and a young pigeon.
And he took unto him all of these, and
divided them in the midst, and laid each
piece one against another, but the birds
he divided not."
Verse 11.
And when the fowls came down upon the
carcasses, Abram drove them away. And
now watch this. And when the sun was
going down, a deep sleep fell upon
Abram. And lo, and horror of great
darkness fell upon him. And he said unto
Abram, "Know of assurityity that thy
seed shall be a stranger in a land that
is not theirs, and shall serve them, and
they shall afflict them 400 years."
and also that nation whom they shall
serve will I judge. And afterward thou
shalt come out with great substance, and
thou shalt go to thy fathers in peace,
and thou shalt be buried in a good old
age, but in the fourth generation they
shall come hither again, for the
iniquity of the Amorites is not yet
full. Continuing,
it says, "And it came to pass that when
the sun went down, and it was dark,
behold, a smoking furnace and a burning
lamp that passed between those pieces.
In the same day the Lord made a covenant
with Abraham, saying, Unto thy seed have
I given this land from the river of
Egypt unto the great unto the great
river, the river Euphrates." Please
note,
please note in this story that Abraham,
Abram
is put into a deep sleep.
And it is during this deep sleep that
God makes a covenant
with him.
I want you to note again, God is showing
Abraham certain things that that that it
may be too painful for him to endure.
Please understand, if you've ever been
put under anesthesia, it is typically
because the surgery that is about to
happen is too painful for you to endure
with all your senses there.
God brings a deep sleep upon Abram
because he's about to show him something
so so bad, so horrible, so horrifying
that Abram may not be able to take it.
But please also note that it is while
Abram is sleeping
that God covenants with Abraham.
There's an animal that is sacrificed and
God walks through the pieces. By the
way, when the when the animal was cut
into pieces and and and and the Bible
says that that God is moving through
these pieces, what would typically
happening happen in those times is that
a covenant where animals cut in pieces.
The two individuals would would walk
between those pieces and would basically
be saying, "Listen, may I become like
this if I don't keep my part of the
covenant?
God lets Abraham sleep,
not just a regular sleep, a deep sleep,
while God himself is the one who walks
through the covenant, who walks through
the pieces. Almost as if God is saying,
"I am the one. This covenant will be one
that I establish with you."
In the book of Genesis, in Genesis
chapters 1 and two, Adam is put into a
deep sleep so that God can work. In the
story of Abraham, Abraham is put into a
deep sleep so that God can work. Let me
take you to another sleep story. Another
sleep story. Come with me to the book of
Daniel. Daniel chapter 8. Daniel is
receiving a vision. It is a vision of a
ram and a hegoat and then this little
horn that rises. And now God is about to
show Daniel something absolutely so
overwhelming that he has to allow Daniel
to go into a deep sleep. Notice with me
Deuteron Daniel 8:1 17. So he came near
where where I stood. And when he came I
was afraid and fell on my face. And he
said unto me, understand son of man, the
vision refers to the time of the end.
Verse 18. Now, as he was speaking with
me, I was in a deep sleep on my face
toward the ground, but he touched me and
set me upright. And he said, "Behold, I
will make you to know what shall be in
the latter end of the indignation. For
at the time of the end, or for at the
time appointed, the end shall be." And
what does he show Daniel? I will just
want to focus on one point here in
Daniel 8:25. And through his policy also
he shall cause craft to prosper in his
hand and he shall magnify himself in his
heart and by peace shall destroy many
and he shall stand up against the prince
of princes but shall be broken without
hand. Daniel is allowed to see
Daniel is allowed to see an attack on
the prince of princes, but ultimately
the prince of princes conquering. And
let me say, let me say that Daniel is
allowed to go into a deep sleep probably
precisely because what he was going to
see was so overwhelming,
so painful, the persecution of God's
people in the future, the the the
crucifying and the persecution of Christ
in person and in his people
that God had to allow Daniel to go into
a deep sleep.
I want you to notice a trend here. I
want you to notice a pattern.
You see
the primary purpose
for anesthesia.
I want to read it to you.
It says here the primary purpose is to
prevent pain and trauma during
procedures.
The primary purpose of putting someone
in a deep sleep is to shut down the pain
and the trauma. When the body's in a
deep sleep, pain and trauma are not
felt. Anxiety and fear are not felt.
Listen closely to closely to me all.
When you are in a deep sleep,
you don't fear.
You are not worried.
Adam is wondering, "What shall I do? I'm
alone. God says, I'm gonna put you in a
deep sleep. Abraham is worried. Uh, what
will the future be? Will I have an air?
How many of you uh know what it's like
to worry? Y'all put a one in the chat if
you know what it's like to worry. If you
know what it's like to be afraid, if you
know what it's like to wonder about the
future, I want you to note what God does
with Adam and what God does with Abraham
and what God even does with Daniel. He
is putting them to sleep in a sense
saying, "Listen, I know what you're
thinking. I know that the pain you're
going through. I know that that what
you're about to see is going to cause
you much much much dismay.
But I need you to see something.
I'm working while you're sleeping.
I am working
while you're sleeping. You see, when
major surgery is going on,
when a doctor understands, I'm doing
this surgery and I don't want you to
feel extreme pain. I don't want the body
to go into shock. I don't want
adrenaline and cortisol to be released
in such a massive uh uh level that it
has a negative effect on the body. So,
so what I'm going to do is I'm going to
put you under I'm going to put you into
a deep sleep so that the doctor can do
his thing.
Y'all put a one in the chat. Y'all put a
one in the chat. If you all of a sudden
are saying to yourself, "Lord,
I need to be put into deep sleep mode."
Put a one in the chat.
That is the message today, beloved. Put
a one in the chat if you're saying to
yourself today, "Lord, put me in deep
sleep mode." Why? Because in deep sleep
mode, God is in total control.
God is in total control. He doesn't need
my worry. He doesn't need my fear. He
doesn't need anything. He says, "You go
to sleep. I have got this. All I need
you to do is sleep."
All I need you to do is sleep. And not
the regular sleep where if you hear a
noise, you wake up. Hey, what was that
noise? I'm like, no, I'm going to put
you into a deep sleep,
a supernatural sleep,
a supernatural rest, so that the things
around you
will have no effect on you. Let me
demonstrate to you. Let me show you what
I'm talking about. Come with me to the
book of Mark. to the book of Mark 4:35
where the Bible says, "And the same day
when the evening was come, he saith unto
them, let us pass over unto the other
side." And when they had sent away the
multitude, they took him even as he was
in the ship. And there were also with
him other little ships. Now, let's pause
for a second. How many of you know this
story? Y'all know the story, right? A
storm is coming.
Jesus says, "Let us go over unto the
other side." Now,
the fact that Jesus spoke those words
meant that they were going to get to the
other side. There was no if ors, or buts
about it. Jesus said it, "Let us go over
to the other side." Jesus is the living
word. And so when he says something, let
us go over to the other side. It is
going to happen. But they get into the
boats. And I want you to notice what
happens in verse 37.
There arose a great storm
of wind and the waves beat into the ship
so that it was now full.
And he, that is Jesus, was in the hind
in the hinder part of the ship. I'm
going to I'm going to just change these
words a little bit if you don't mind.
In a
deep sleep,
Jesus
in the midst of the storm was in, say it
with me everybody, a deep sleep.
He was asleep on a pillow.
And they wake him and say unto him,
"Master, carest thou not that we perish?
Just pause for a second and think about
that.
Beloved, I believe in this story, Jesus
is attempting to demonstrate to the
disciples what it means to have deep
sleep. What it means to have deep rest.
What it means to be so fully sleeping
and resting in trust, in faith, that the
crazy things that are going on around
you have no effect on you. It's almost
as if you are in a trance, beloved.
Listen to me. It's as if Jesus is
saying, "Listen, true rest in me is like
a divine trance that the devil cannot
wake you up out of."
Because I want you to understand that
the only one that wants you to wake up
out of this trance, this deep sleep,
this deep abiding trust, this deep
abiding faith, this deep abiding rest is
Satan himself.
Wake up. Snap out of that peace.
Snap out of that trust.
God puts Adam to sleep so that he can
work. Adam, you have a need. Listen, you
don't you don't go about trying to get
that need yourself. I'm going to put you
to sleep. You just rest while I
accomplish the thing.
Abraham, I know you're worried and
you're even worried about the land and
the future. Hey, listen. I got to show
you something, but I'm going to put you
to sleep.
So that you could see those things. So
that you could see the future and not be
dismayed.
And I want you to understand that even
while you're sleeping, I am making the
covenant. I need you to trust me. I got
this. I got you,
man. If only Abraham had really really
uh
slept,
stayed in a deep sleep,
but uh you know his wife woke him up,
was like, "Hey, are you sure this
promise is coming through?"
Beloved, our our our
fight in the fight of faith is to learn
how to sleep deeply.
Our fight in the fight of faith is learn
how to deep sleep. How to be in such a
deep sleep in Christ that no matter what
the enemy does, he cannot wake you up.
So despite the pain and despite the
suffering you beloved listen to me
anesthesia is can be one of the most
comforting things
if you're in pain
like ask the pregnant moms
who when they get that epidural when
they they're not going fully to sleep
but when they get that epid when they
get that thing that eases the pain
how How comforting that is.
Lord, help us. Help me to understand
what it means to be in deep sleep so
that God can do what he has to do in my
life without me waking up every God, you
doing it?
God, you doing it? I'm sleeping, but you
doing it. No, no, no, no, no. Lord,
teach me to sleep deeply. Oh, Clint.
Lazarus.
Lazarus our brother. Lazarus
our friend. Lazarus
sleep.
Listen. Jesus in the storm is so
settled in his father's protection that
he's asleep
in the midst of the crisis. asleep in
the midst of the storm. And the Bible
says that after they wake him up because
they're they are terrified. They're not
sleeping. They're awake.
And look at what Jesus said. He arose
and rebuked the wind and said unto the
sea, "Peace, be still, and the wind
ceased.
And there was a great calm. And he said
unto them, why are ye so fearful? How is
it that you have no what?"
Y'all want to know what faith is? Faith
is a state of deep sleep.
Faith is deep sleeping in Jesus. Faith
is deep sleeping in in the father's
love, in the father's protection. Faith
is deep sleeping in the midst of chaos.
It is deep sleeping in the midst of
confidence. And now watch this. Jesus
wants to give us this deep sleep. Notice
Matthew 11:28 where he says, "Come unto
me all ye that labor and are heavy laden
and I will give you rest. I will give
you deep sleep, y'all.
I will give you the power. I will give
you a rest so deep that it'll be like a
trance."
Y'all put a one in the chat if you want
deep sleep.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Think about think
about all the suffering. Think about all
the trials. Think about all the things
that feel like they're driving you to
the edge. Think about all those things.
And then imagine what it would be like
to just
sleep
deeply.
Lord, if there is one thing that we
need, it is to deep. It is to sleep
deeply. It is to sleep so deeply that no
matter what storms come our way, what
winds blow our way, we are sleeping.
Listen. Psalms 4:8. Notice what the
Bible says here. I will both lay me down
in peace and sleep. For thou, Lord, only
makest me dwell in safety. In Psalm
23:2, he maketh me to lie down in green
pastures. He leads me beside quiet
waters. Sh, I'm sleeping.
And beloved, when you're in a deep
sleep, no matter how much noise the
devil makes,
no matter how much noise the devil
makes, you're not waking up.
You're not waking up. I see y'all
putting the verses in the in the chat,
the verses that are coming to your mind
right now. Like, pastor, what about
this? What about that? I see it all. And
and by the grace of God, he's bringing
it all together for you. Yes. Yes. Yes.
He's bringing it all together for you.
Listen, the other reason that physicians
will put someone to sleep is to prevent
movement. I don't know if y'all
listening to me now.
It is to prevent movement during
precision procedures.
You see, some surgeries require absolute
stillness.
Absolute stillness.
If that's brain surgery, heart surgery,
spinal surgery, eye surgery, absolute
stillness. And I need you to understand,
beloved,
that when God is operating on the mind
or on the heart or on the spine, you
know, backbone so you can stand or on
the eye so you can have new vision. He
needs you to be absolutely
still because surgical error, beloved.
And God is not the error will not be on
God's part. The error would be on our
part.
So deep anesthesia brings you into a
position where there is zero voluntary
movement. And this is why beloved, the
Bible says in Psalm 46:10, "Be still and
know
that I am God."
Be still you all, and know that I am
God. And so I want you to understand,
beloved, that this deep sleep of Adam
and this deep sleep of Abraham and this
deep sleep of Daniel and this deep sleep
of Jesus in the boat really all pointed
forward to one and to the greatest deep
sleep of all time. And that deep sleep,
beloved, began in the garden of
Gethsemane.
It began, beloved, we're not we're not
going to the screen. I just want want to
I need you to catch this. Remember that
in the garden of Gethsemane, Jesus knows
that he's about to go into a deep sleep.
And so he goes into the garden to pray.
He knows he's about to go into that
sleep of death. And so he goes into the
garden to pray. And while he's praying,
beloved, his disciples are actually in a
deep sleep. The wrong deep sleep.
They're in the wrong kind of stuper.
Jesus is preparing to go into the
greatest sleep ever, the deepest sleep
of all mankind, the the most important
deep sleep ever, which would be his
sleep on the cross, his sleep in the
tomb. And you'll remember that as he's
speaking to to to the Jews, he actually
says this. But he answered and said unto
them, "An evil and adulterous generation
seeketh after a sign, and there shall no
sign be given it, but the sign of the
prophet Jonah. For as Jonah was in the
was three days and three nights in the
whale's belly, so shall the Son of Man
be three days and three nights in the
heart of the earth." Now, I need to
break something down to you about the
story of Jonah. Because you might
remember
that before Jonah enters into this
three-day, three night experience in the
belly of the of the fish. You might
remember that Jonah is on the boat and
Jonah,
a storm comes.
And I want you to note what the Bible
says about this storm. The the the
people in the boat are terrified. The
Bible says, "Then the mariners were
afraid and cried every man unto his God
and cast forth the wares that were in
the ship into the sea to lighten it of
them. But Jonah was gone down into the
sides of the ship, and he and he lay and
was
fast asleep."
Now I need you to understand beloved
that the sleep of Jonah
in his boat in that boat was very
different from the sleep of Jonah of
Jesus in his boat. Let me say it again.
The sleep of Jonah in his boat. The deep
sleep he was in in the midst of a storm
in his boat was very different from the
deep sleep Jesus was in in his boat. But
it's interesting how Jonah is first
asleep in the boat and then he will
enter into this three-day three-ight
experience. It's as if Gona was Jesus
was saying, "I am the second Jonah, but
I'm not going to fail where Jonah
failed."
And so, while Jesus is is is is sleeping
on his boat and they wake him up, carest
thou not that we perish, instead of
Jesus throwing himself overboard, Jesus
just says to the storm, "Peace be still.
Peace be still.
You know, when you
when a surgeon puts you under, the whole
goal is for you to be still.
It's as if Jesus was not only talking to
the storm, saying, "Peace, be still." He
was talking to them. Y'all need to be
still. Disciples.
You need to be still.
I'm trying to operate here and y'all are
moving around in fear. Y'all are moving
around in discouragement. Y'all are
moving around in anxiety. Y'all are
moving I'm trying to operate and you
you're you're risking it all by not
being still. Stay still.
Stay still.
I need you to sleep deeply. See my
example on the boat. Y'all should have
been sleeping. Y'all should have been
sleeping deeply knowing that I had
already said, "Let us go over to the
other side." So if I said, "Let us go
over to the other side," what makes you
think that the boat was not going to
make it to the other side?
Am I not the living word?
Shall my word come back to me void?
Come on, y'all. Jesus is saying,
"Where's your faith?" Faith comes by
hearing and hearing by the word of God.
So how are you so little faith? Why is
he saying that? Because you heard me
say, "Let us go over to the other side."
Why did you doubt that we were not going
to get to the other side if I said let
us go over to the other side?
And so now Jesus, beloved, is now
getting ready to enter into that sleep
of sleeps, the deepest sleep, the sleep
of death, the sleep of the cross.
And this is so beautiful, beloved,
because I want you to see, beloved, that
in this sleep of the cross, in this
sleep of the tomb, Jesus, listen to me,
Jesus is fulfilling the sleep of Adam.
Y'all put a seven in the chat. Y'all put
a seven in the chat if y'all just got
just got
Did y'all see that just now?
The very sleep that Adam experienced,
he's put to sleep so that his side can
be opened up. Out of which will come his
bride.
Jesus in that sleep of death
is doing is is experiencing is is
reliving as the second Adam he's being
put to sleep. Notice John 19:34. One of
the soldiers with a spear pierced his
side and forth with came their out blood
and water. Out of the pierced side of
the last Adam comes his bride, the New
Testament church.
Not only is Jesus fulfilling the sleep
of Adam in his sleep at the cross, he's
fulfilling Abraham's deep sleep as well.
You will remember
that God says to Abraham, to Abram, I
want you to take these animals and how
old were these animals? Three years old.
Almost as if they had been raised to get
to a certain age. And then at that
certain age, Abraham, I want you to
sacrifice these animals. And beloved,
this is pointing to the death of Jesus.
Abraham saw the death of Christ.
And beloved, that's probably why God had
to put him to sleep.
When Jesus said, Abraham saw my day,
God had to buffer.
God had to buffer that. Listen to this.
Not only not only does Abraham fall
asleep and this while this sacrifice is
h or and this sacrifice happens, the
sacrifice happens and God shows Abraham
the future. God puts Abraham to sleep
and says, "I'm making a covenant with
you." But a but God is the one walking
through the pieces of the animal
himself. In other words, Jesus took our
sins upon him and he tread the wine
press of the wrath of God alone.
And beloved, I want you to think about
this. You know, in the Bible when it
says that not a bone of Jesus's body was
to be broken,
may I suggest, may I suggest that when
God said to Abraham, I want you to cut
this animal in pieces.
So, the animal was being divided and
then God was going to walk through the
animal. Abraham didn't walk through it.
God walked through it. And the Bible
tells us the Bible tells us or or or uh
um
culture tells us that and history tells
us that the whole purpose of the animals
being cut was listen if I fail in the
covenant then I let what happened to
this animal being divided happened to
me.
Could it be possible that the reason
Jesus bones are not broken is because he
fulfilled the very covenant and the very
promise he made?
Beloved, I want you to think about the
richness of that.
Not a bone, no bone in his body is to be
separated because he kept the covenant.
Because he kept the promise. You sleep.
I got it. I got this. Abra, Abram, you
sleep.
You sleep.
You sleep. Daniel's deep sleep. Jesus
not only fulfilled Abraham's deep sleep,
he not only fulfilled Adam's deep sleep,
he fulfilled Daniel's deep sleep.
Because remember what Daniel sees when
God when he when he goes into a deep
sleep and then the angel comes to
explain him as if that deep sleep was
preparing Daniel to hear what he was
about to hear. One of the things that it
said is that he shall stand up against
the prince of princes but he shall be
broken without hand. Daniel 8:25. I need
you to understand this, beloved, because
in in Genesis 3:15, the Bible says, "I
will put enmity between thee and the
woman, between thy seed and her seed. It
shall bruise thy head, and thou shalt
bruise his heel." In Jesus's death, the
prince of the covenant breaks without
hand the serpent. It is the beginning of
that breaking, but he breaks the serpent
nonetheless. We know that this little
horn power goes on to represent it is
first Rome and then it is the papacy and
ultimately it'll be the enemy himself.
But in but what Jesus does in his death,
listen to me.
Jesus beat the devil in his sleep.
Yes.
Y'all ever hear people like, "Man, I
could beat you in my sleep." Jesus
literally beat the enemy in his sleep.
And now I need you to understand
something, beloved.
It is in sleep that we beat the enemy.
It is in sleep that we beat the devil.
It is in sleep that we beat fear. It is
in sleep, deep sleep, that we beat
anxiety. It is in deep sleep that we
beat worry. It is in deep sleep that we
beat depression. It is in deep sleep
that we beat the enemy's whispers to us.
Because when you're in deep sleep, you
don't hear anything. You can't see
anything. You don't feel anything. And
Jesus is saying, "Listen, when you enter
into my deep sleep,
the enemy will try to rouse you and wake
you up and cause you to worry and fear.
But don't worry because when you are in
when you are experiencing the deep sleep
of the spirit,
that is where your victory is. You can
beat the devil in your sleep.
Who would have thought? Who would have
thought? You got to be awake. And I All
right, devil.
If you sleep, if you deep sleep, if you
be still, stand still, and see the
salvation of the Lord. If you just
sleep, sleep deeply,
I can do what I need to do.
When you keep moving around in the
surgery, you keep moving, you keep
moving around in fear and anxiety and
worry,
you're causing more problems for
yourself.
Sleep and sleep deeply.
And now, now I want you to understand
something, beloved, because I want to go
back to that to that Jesus, that story
of Jesus in the boat. Because remember
when Jesus said,
as we just pointed out, when Jesus said,
"Let us go over to the other side."
I need you to understand the beautiful
symbolism of
going over to the other side.
Follow me on this journey. We're going
over to the other side. But I need you
to understand, beloved, that in life,
our whole goal as Christians is to get
over to the other side. Put a seven in
the chat if you would like to get over
to the other side.
Yeah, that's it. We want to get over to
the other side. We want to get over to
the kingdom of heaven. So when Jesus
said, "Let's get in these boats and let
us go over to the other side." I need
you to understand that as we're in this
journey, there going to be storms.
There's going to be trials. There's
going to be different things that are
going to test your faith, but I need you
to just sleep deeply on the way.
Y'all go to sleep. I'm on the ship. Go
to sleep. I'll wake you up when we get
there.
And the problem, beloved, is that so
many of us don't know how to sleep.
We don't know
how to sleep deeply. We sleep lightly.
We sleep lightly.
We don't know. We've never asked, "Lord,
put me into a deep sleep.
Put me into a deep sleep."
Because, beloved, Jesus is the one that
is leading us over to the other side.
And if you think, hey, what story in the
Bible, what story in the Bible do does
God lead a people to the other side? If
I were you, I would be thinking of the
Exodus. How many of you would be
thinking about the Exodus? How many of
you would think about the Exodus where
where God literally leads them
over the Red Sea
unto the other side.
This was their journey to the promised
land. But there's something very
specific that I want you to see about
this journey, you guys.
Because remember earlier earlier when we
were looking at Abraham's deep sleep and
God does something interesting. Remember
when the Bible says when it got dark
that Abraham
uh in this deep sleep sees a f a smoking
furnace
and a
burning lamp.
So smoke and fire. Smoke and fire. And
they are going through these cut pieces
and you're saying smoke and fire, smoke
and fire, pastor, smoke and fire, smoke
and fire. Why is God showing Abraham a
symbol of smoke, a symbol of smoke and
fire when he's talking about what the
children of Israel will go through for
400 years and then what will happen at
the end of that 400 years in answer to
Abraham's question, how will I know that
I will inherit this land?
You might remember, you might remember
in Exodus 13:21 that the Bible says,
"And the Lord went before them by day in
a pillar of a cloud to lead them the
way, and by night in a pillar of fire."
Whoa.
Cloud and fire. Smoke and fire. Y'all
not feeling me? Smoke and fire.
smoke by day, fire by night. God is the
one leading them. Now remember remember
that that when the animal is cut in
pieces, it is a symbol of death. G as it
were is walking through death.
That vision shows God walking through
death
literally.
And here we have in the Exodus, God as a
as a as a smoke and fire leading the
children of Israel. Let's keep reading.
He went the Lord went before them by day
in a pillar of cloud to lead them by the
way, and by night in a pillar of fire to
give them light to go by day and night.
He took not away the pillar of the cloud
by day, nor the pillar of fire by night
from before the people. And now you'll
remember that just before they're
getting ready to cross the Red Sea, the
Bible says, "And the angel of God which
went before the camp of Israel removed
and went behind them and the pillar of
the cloud went be went from before their
faith at their face and stood behind
them." Watch this. And it came between
the camp of the Egyptians and the camp
of Israel. And it was a cloud and
darkness to them, but it gave light by
night to these so that the one came not
near the other.
Could it be that God was telling
Abraham, "Listen, I will protect your
offspring. Listen, I understand what
what what I'm telling you now is is is
troubling, but I want to let you know
that I will protect them. I will do this
in your sleep. I could do this in my
sleep.
Jesus is leading them through death.
He's leading them through the valley.
Yay. Yay. Yay. Though I walk through the
valley
of the shadow
of death of deep sleep.
I will not fear.
Wow. I will fear no evil. Why? Because
I'm sleeping.
Why? Because I'm in a deep sleep.
The Bible tells us in Isaiah 30:15, "For
thus sayith the Lord God, the Holy One
of Israel, in returning and rest shall
you be saved. In quietness and
confidence shall be your strength." In
Christ's death, beloved, in Jesus's
death, in Jesus's deep sleep, he
fulfilled the sleep of Adam, he
fulfilled the sleep of Abraham, he
fulfilled the sleep of Daniel. He
fulfilled the sleep of Jonah. He
fulfilled the sleep of himself in the
boat. Jesus is saying to to to us, do
not be afraid of deep sleep.
Because listen,
when you deep sleep
in me, when I come to wake you up,
you'll be like, "Oh, what happened?
What happened?
Wait, what?
Wait, you mean while I was sleeping this
and this and this and this and Whoa."
Yes, Gigi. Holy hibernation.
I want you to understand, beloved, as as
we're getting ready to close, I want you
to understand
that God is calling us to sleep deeply
because he knows that that
we will all face the ultimate deep
sleep.
And the Bible tells us in 1
Thessalonians chapter 4:15, "For this we
say unto you by the word of the Lord,
that we which are alive and remain unto
the coming of the Lord shall not pre
prevent them which are asleep. For the
Lord himself shall descend from heaven
with a shout, with the voice of the
archangel, and with the trump of God,
and the dead in Christ shall rise first.
Then we which are alive and remain shall
be caught up together with them in the
clouds to meet the Lord in the air. And
so shall we ever be with the Lord."
Guys, do you deep sleep? Do you deep
sleep?
Because only those that deep sleep
will be the ones to enter the kingdom of
heaven when Jesus comes to wake up his
deep sleepers.
You understand?
When you're a deep sleeper, nobody but
nobody but God can wake you up.
The devil can't wake you.
The people the devil sends to get you
mad can't wake you.
When you can when God is the only one
that can wake you. And when that time
comes, the right time to be when when
that's the case, beloved, you are
resting in peace. And that's what Jesus
wants. He wants you to rest in peace.
And listen, guys, I need you to see
this, okay? I need we're this is our
final picture. This our closing picture.
So remember how you had Abraham having
this having this this vision of the of
of uh the covenant and the animal being
sacrificed and then and then after that
you have this 400year period right where
the children of Israel are in in
captivity and then after that you have
the exodus and the exodus is leading
them into the promised land. Okay so
remember that remember that layout.
Well, if if Jesus
is the fulfillment of that covenant,
then we need to ask ourselves, what is
the 400year period, the parallel to the
400-year period after this sacrifice
that would that would happen after the
sacrifice of Christ, who is the
fulfillment of that covenant. And
beloved, lo and behold, the book of
Revelation tells us tells us that there
is a 1,260-year
period in which God's people will go
through a persecution much like the 400
years of Abraham's offspring.
Are y'all following?
So then, so then if at the end of the
400 years there is an exodus, a a
calling out of Egypt, then we must
probably conclude we it is likely that
we should conclude that at the end of
this 1260 years, there would also come
the beginning of a calling out
from this persecuting power.
Are y'all following me? Are y'all
catching a Are y'all catching the
parallel?
And here's what I want you to lock in
on, guys.
It is after the coming out of of of
Egypt and in in a spiritual context,
after the coming out of Babylon that the
people of God begin their journey into
the promised land.
What is that land called?
What did God promise them in that land?
He promised them
rest.
And and beloved, please understand
that that this is why
this is why here's our closing verse,
you guys. This is why
Hebrews 4:9 tells us, "There remainth
therefore a rest to the people of God.
For he that has entered into his rest
has also ceased from his own works, as
God did from his." Let us labor
therefore to enter into that rest.
You guys,
only those who rest
will make it into the rest.
And this is why Paul says, "Let us labor
therefore to enter into that rest." Our
work is to rest. Our work is to sleep
deeply.
So my appeal,
my appeal
is Lord,
show me
how to sleep deeply.
Lead me into deep sleep. Lord,
instruct me.
In fact, Lord, I pray just put me into a
deep sleep in Christ.
I remember one of the last things my
brother said
uh before he died
was that he just wanted to go into a
deep sleep.
I I wasn't there when he said it. The
nurse
told us as
he had a few hours to live and he said,
"I just want to go into a deep sleep."
And
it is interesting. I I have never been
put under before,
but
um
several months back
um I had this procedure done where I was
put under
And I remember when I came out of that
procedure,
the first thing I did was I started
crying. I started crying and you know
doctor was like everything is good you
know everything is fine you're good and
then I just started crying. I mean
literally like I remember waking up. I
remember the doctor standing over me.
Everything is good.
And then I started crying
and I started he he he asked why are you
crying? And I said,
"My brother recently died
and
I'm crying because
going into sleep like this where I felt
nothing. I knew nothing and like coming
out of the sleep was just like wait I
was sleeping."
No, no, no, John. Crying is not a common
response. My brother was on my mind.
That's why I was crying.
And I remember think I remember saying
to him,
if this is what my brother
felt
and if this is what he will feel when he
wakes up,
then I'm good.
I'm good.
And beloved, that that moment of of rest
in which
there was nothing happening mentally,
it was like one of the deepest things I
had ever experienced. And when I
combined it with with losing my brother,
it was it was a very emotional
experience for me.
What will it be like when Jesus comes
again to wake us up out of sleep? And
we're like,
wait, the last, you know, when the
doctor was counted down, I'm going to
count down to seven. I'm going to count
down to 10 uh backwards and then and all
I remember was seven. 10 9 8 7
nothing else. That was it.
What a beautiful thing it will be when
Jesus comes to wake his people out of
their deep sleep.
And beloved, to understand that we can
experience deep sleep now.
Lord, put me in that holy
spiritual deep sleep so that nothing in
this world can wake me up except
you.
That's where we ought to be.
So, put that seven in the chat if you're
saying, "Lord, put me in a deep sleep.
Lord, teach me how to sleep deeply.
Teach me how to sleep deeply." If that
is you,
praise God. Put that seven in the chat.
Let us pray. Heavenly Father,
Lord, there is so much pain and
suffering in this world. There is so
much anguish. There is so much worry.
There is so much doubt, uncertainty,
fear.
Lord, we are praying today
that you would put your people into deep
sleep mode.
And Lord, that we will stay in deep
sleep mode while you do the operation
that needs to be done on each one of us.
operate on our minds, operate on our
hearts, operate on our spines, operate
on our eyes, operate on our ears, Lord,
so that when
you wake us up at that second coming
where some of us will be translated and
some of us will be will translated
without seeing death and some of us will
be raised from the grave, but all of us
will be waking up at that time
to who we are to be for all eternity.
Reflectors of your glory.
May that day
bring rejoicing,
tears of joy
and celebration, Lord.
And so until then, Lord, please
teach us to rest deeply,
to sleep deeply, so that no storm, no
crisis, no challenge
can wake us up from that comfortable
comforter
pillow
like Jesus slept on in that boat.
May we sleep through the sin and the
chaos of this world until you come again
when we get to that and we get to that
other side. In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
And amen.
Praise God you guys. Um
we're going to go ahead and put that
link uh in the chat for our afterlow
discussion. Um, let me go ahead and put
up this last slide so you can see where
you can connect with Living Mana uh
where you can uh submit your prayer
requests and also if you are wanting to
do Bible studies, wanting to prepare for
baptism, please email our Bible worker
at living.urch.
Again, you guys, may God bless you, may
God keep you, and um may God teach you
to sleep deeply.
Amen. And amen.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.